A Guide to the Elizabeth Oakes Smith Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8326-a
Elizabeth Oakes Smith Collection 1843-1883
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8326-a
10 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit [ 1963 Dec 17 ] 1967 Feb 21
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - " A Visit to Long Island ", AMs, 6 p.
- Letters
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1843 Jul 18; ALS, 2 p.
    [Acknowledges his letter containing a draft; hopes the article she sends him will be acceptable.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to Messrs. Carey and Hart, 1847 Nov 18; ALS, 1 p.
    [Accepts the firm's statement that she had prepared only 5 manuscripts for them; says she had erroneously thought of a higher number.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to "My dear Doctor", 1850 May 6; ALS, 4 p.
    [Encourages an ill friend; reports on her play to be staged in September in Philadelphia; says she is afraid that one book project has fallen through; feels that the past year has been a loss to her; encloses an article by John Neal; asks correspondent to get a copy of her portrait should he go to Philadelphia, where the portrait was done.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to Messrs. Ticknor and Fields, 1853 Jun 25; ALS, 2 p.
    [Discusses one of her plays which has been well received by the press, especially by [George] Ripley of the
    New York Times
    hopes to see it introduced to the Boston public; requests that they send copies of that play to all the principal editors of Boston. ]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to Rufus Wilmot Griswold, 1853 Jul 1; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses a play of hers which he endorsed in his book years ago; asks him to review
    Old New York
    (1853) in some papers, having received many literary courtesies from him in the past; complains about the lack of companionship among contemporary writers.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to E[dwin] P[ercy] Whipple, 1854 Dec 23; ALS, 1 p.
    [Encloses a volume of poems by Caroline [Briggs] of Marblehead whom she thinks highly of; asks him the favor of receiving them.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to M. Laird Simms, 1873 Aug 4; ALS, 2 p.
    [Complains that the
    Cyclopedia of American Literature
    gives little idea of her writings; gives him a list of titles of her recent writings.]
  - Elizabeth Oakes Smith to Editor, Portland Daily Press, 1873 Oct 17; ALS, 1 p.
    [Says she would like to know if her letter containing reminiscences of her honored friend Judge [Ware] has reached him; says she is certain, should there be interest, any New York paper would be glad to have them; asks for a reply.]
  - "The measure of capacity is the measure of Sphere to either man or woman. Elizabeth Oakes Smith. ", 1883 Aug 14; AQS,